The Pentagon just
blacklisted one of
America's leading AI
companies for saying
no Anthropic built
Claude to be
the safe one
the careful one
the AI company
that asks what
could go wrong
before shipping Now
the Department of
Defense wanted full
access all lawful
purposes no restrictions
Anthropic said no
They wouldn't sign
away control of
their models to
the military machine
Within weeks the
Pentagon labeled them
a supply chain
risk to national
security barred from
defense contracts effective
immediately Senator Warren
called it retaliation
Tech workers started
circulating open letters
Anthropic filed suit
calling the action
unprecedented and unlawful
But here's what
this is really
about Anthropic is
betting that courts
will protect the
company's right to
choose its customers
The Pentagon is
betting it won't
need to ask
If you're building
AI products this
changes the game
Every enterprise contract
every government RFP
every unrestricted access
clause now has
a different weight
Can you actually
say no to
your biggest customer
Or does signing
mean surrendering control
of what you
built Anthropic built
guardrails into their
AI Now they're
finding out if
they can build
guardrails around their
company Can you
This is Crux